{"questions":[{"question":"With which of the following statements concerning the stiffening of aging tissues would the author most likely agree?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"It is caused to a large degree by an increased rate of cell multiplication."},{"key":"B","answer":"It paradoxically both helps and hinders the longevity of proteins in the human body"},{"key":"C","answer":"It can be counteracted in part by increased ingestion of glucose-free foods."},{"key":"D","answer":"It is exacerbated by increased enzymatic glycosylation."},{"key":"E","answer":"It probably involves the nonenzymatic glycosylation of proteins."}],"right":["E"],"parent":0},{"question":"According to the passage, which of the following statements is true of the process that discolors and toughens foods?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"It takes place more slowly than glycosylation in the human body."},{"key":"B","answer":"It requires a higher ratio of glucose to protein than glycosylation requires in the human body."},{"key":"C","answer":"It does not require the aid of enzymes to attach glucose to protein."},{"key":"D","answer":"It proceeds more quickly when the food proteins have a molecular structure similar to that of crystallin proteins."},{"key":"E","answer":"Its effectiveness depends heavily on the amount of environmental moisture. "}],"right":["C"],"parent":0},{"question":" According to the passage, which of the following is characteristic of enzymatic glycosylation of proteins?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"AGE's are formed after a period of months or years."},{"key":"B","answer":"Proteins affected by the process are made unstable. "},{"key":"C","answer":"Glucose attachment impairs and stiffens tissues."},{"key":"D","answer":"Glucose is attached to proteins for specific purposes. "},{"key":"E","answer":"Amino groups combine with aldehyde groups to form Schiff bases. "}],"right":["D"],"parent":0},{"question":" According to the passage, which of the following statements is true of Amadori products in proteins?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"They are more plentiful in a dehydrated environment."},{"key":"B","answer":"They are created through enzymatic glycosylation"},{"key":"C","answer":"They are composed entirely of glucose molecules."},{"key":"D","answer":"They are derived from Schiff bases."},{"key":"E","answer":"They are derived from AGE's "}],"right":["D"],"parent":0},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the function of the third paragraph of the passage (lines 19-29)?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":" It offers evidence that contradicts the findings described in the first two paragraphs"},{"key":"B","answer":" It presents a specific example of the process discussed in the first two paragraphs. "},{"key":"C","answer":"It explains a problem that the researchers mentioned in the second paragraph have yet to solve."},{"key":"D","answer":" It evaluates the research discoveries described in the previous paragraph"},{"key":"E","answer":" It begins a detailed description of the process introduced in the previous two paragraphs. "}],"right":["E"],"parent":0},{"question":"The passage suggests that which of the following would be LEAST important in determining whether nonenzymatic glycosylation is likely to have taken place in the proteins of a particular tissue?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"The likelihood that the tissue has been exposed to free glucose."},{"key":"B","answer":"The color and spectrographic properties of structures within the tissue."},{"key":"C","answer":"The amount of time that the proteins in the tissue have persisted in the body."},{"key":"D","answer":"The number of amino groups within the proteins in the tissue."},{"key":"E","answer":"The degree of elasticity that the tissue exhibits."}],"right":["D"],"parent":0},{"question":"If the hypothesis stated in lines 56-58 is true, it can be inferred that the crystallin proteins in the lenses of people with cataracts","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"have increased elasticity"},{"key":"B","answer":"do not respond to enzymatic glycosylation"},{"key":"C","answer":"are more susceptible to stiffening than are other proteins"},{"key":"D","answer":"are at least several months old"},{"key":"E","answer":"respond more acutely than other proteins to changes in moisture levels"}],"right":["D"],"parent":0},{"question":"The primary purpose of the passage is to","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"question the published conclusions of a scholar concerning the history of the Iroquois nation "},{"key":"B","answer":" establish the relationship between an earlierscholar's work and new anthropological research"},{"key":"C","answer":"summarize scholarly controversy concerning an incident from Iroquois history"},{"key":"D","answer":"trace two generations of scholarly opinion concerning Iroquois social institutions "},{"key":"E","answer":"differentiate between Iroquois political practices and Iroquois religious practices"}],"right":["A"],"parent":1},{"question":" It can be inferred that the author of the passage regards Smith's argument as ","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"provocative and potentially useful, but flawed by poor organization"},{"key":"B","answer":"eloquently presented, but needlessly inflammatory"},{"key":"C","answer":"accurate in some of its particulars, but inaccurate with regard to an important point."},{"key":"D","answer":"historically sound, but overly detailed and redundant "},{"key":"E","answer":"persuasive in its time, but now largely outdated"}],"right":["C"],"parent":1},{"question":"The author of the passage implies that which of the following occurred after the Iroquois were resettled on reservations early in the nineteenth century?","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"Chiefs became more involved in their tribe's religious affairs"},{"key":"B","answer":"The authority of the chief's council over the affairs of individual tribes increased"},{"key":"C","answer":"The political influence of the Iroquois shamans was diminished. "},{"key":"D","answer":"individual tribes coalesced into the Iroquois tribal league. "},{"key":"E","answer":"The longhouse because a political rather than a religious institution."}],"right":["B"],"parent":1},{"question":"Which of the following best expresses an opinion presented by the author of the passage? ","options":[{"key":"A","answer":"Smith has overstated the importance of the political role played by Iroquois tribal chiefs in the nineteenth century. "},{"key":"B","answer":" Smith has overlooked the fact that the Iroquois rarely allowed their shamans to exercise political authority"},{"key":"C","answer":"Smith has failed to explain why the chief's council was dissolved late in the nineteenth century. "},{"key":"D","answer":" Smith has failed to acknowledge the role prior to the nineteenth century of the Iroquois tribal chiefs in religious affairs. "},{"key":"E","answer":"Smith has failed to recognize that the very structure of Iroquois social institutions reflects religious beliefs."}],"right":["D"],"parent":1}],"parent":["As people age, their cells become less efficient and\nless able to replace damaged components. At the same\ntime their tissues stiffen. For example, the lungs and the\nheart muscle expand less successfully, the blood vessels\n(5) become increasingly rigid, and the ligaments and tendons\ntighten.\nFew investigators would attribute such diverse effects\nto a single cause. Nevertheless, researchers have discovered that a\n process long known to discolor and toughen\n(10)foods may also contribute to age- related impairment of\nboth cells and tissues. That process is nonenzymatic\nglycosylation, whereby glucose becomes attached to proteins without \nthe aid of enzymes. When enzymes attach\nglucose to proteins (enzymatic glycosylation), they do so\n(15)at a specific site on a specific protein molecule for a\nspecific purpose. In contrast, the nonenzymatic process\nadds glucose haphazardly to any of several sites along\nany available peptide chain within a protein molecule.\nThis nonenzymatic glycosylation of certain proteins\n(20)has been understood by food chemists for decades,\nalthough few biologists recognized until recently that the\nsame steps could take place in the body. Nonenzymatic\nglycosylation begins when an aldehyde group (CHO) of\nglucose and an amino group (NH2) of a protein are\n(25)attracted to each other. The molecules combine, forming\nwhat is called a Schiff base within the protein. This combination \nis unstable and quickly rearranges itself into a\nstabler, but still reversible, substance known as an\nAmadori product.\n(30) If a given protein persists in the body for months or\nyears, some of its Amadori products slowly dehydrate and\nrearrange themselves yet again, into new glucose-derived\nstructures. These can combine with various kinds of molecules\n to form irreversible structures named advanced\n(35)glycosylation end products (AGE's). Most AGE's are\nyellowish brown and fluorescent and have specific spectrographic \nproperties. More important for the body, many\nare also able to cross-link adjacent proteins, particularly\nones that give structure to tissues and organs. Although\n(40)no one has yet satisfactorily described the origin of all\nsuch bridges between proteins, many investigators agree\nthat extensive cross-linking of proteins probably contri-\nbutes to the stiffening and loss of elasticity characteristic\nof aging tissues.\n(45) In an attempt to link this process with the developme-\nnt of cataracts (the browning and clouding of the lens\nof the eye as people age), researchers studied the effect\nof glucose on solutions of purified crystallin, the major\nprotein in the lens of the eye. Glucose-free solutions\n(50) remained clear, but solutions with glucose caused the\nproteins to form clusters, suggesting that the molecules\nhad become cross-linked. The clusters diffracted light,\nmaking the solution opaque. The researchers also\ndiscovered that the pigmented cross-links in human\n(55)cataracts have the brownish color and fluorescence\ncharacteristic of AGE's. These data suggest that\nnonenzymatic glycosylation of lens crystallins may\ncontribute to cataract formation.\n","Writing of the Iroquois nation, Smith has argued that\nthrough the chiefs' council, tribal chiefs traditionally\nmaintained complete control over the political affairs of\nboth the Iroquois tribal league and the individual tribes\n(5) belonging to the league, whereas the sole jurisdiction\nover religious affairs resided with the shamans.\nAccording to Smith, this division was maintained until\nthe late nineteenth century, when the dissolution of the\nchiefs' council and the consequent diminishment of the\n(10) chiefs' political power fostered their increasing involvement in religious affairs.\nHowever, Smith fails to recognize that this division of\npower between the tribal chiefs and shamans was not\nactually rooted in Iroquois tradition; rather, it resulted\n(15) from the Iroquois' resettlement on reservations early in\nthe nineteenth century. Prior to resettlement, the chiefs'\ncouncil controlled only the broad policy of the tribal\nleague; individual tribes had institutions― most important, the longhouse― to govern their own affairs. In the\n(20) longhouse, the tribe's chief influenced both political and\nreligious affairs."]}